{"id":"2018_8","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"The Lord came and stood there, calling as at the other times, 'Samuel, Samuel!' Then Samuel said, 'Speak, for your servant is listening.' \" â€“ 1 Samuel 3:10","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_8_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_8_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 1 Samuel 4-5.\nGod revealed His power over the Philistine gods.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"4:1-5:12"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_8_3","questionText":"3. What was the ark of the covenant? What did the Israelites hope to accomplish by taking it into battle? (See Exodus 25:10-22; Numbers 7:89; 1 Samuel 4:22; Hebrews 9:1-4.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Exodus","verse":"25:10-22"},{"book":"Numbers","verse":"7:89"},{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"4:22"},{"book":"Hebrews","verse":"9:1-4"}]},{"id":"2018_8_4","questionText":"4. Trace the effects of the ark's presence in these chapters. What lessons do you learn about God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_8_5","questionText":"5. How are Christians guilty of trying to use God or His Word to get what they want today?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 1 Samuel 6.\nGod revealed His power and holiness to the Philistines and Israelites as the ark was returned to Israel.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"6:1-21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_8_6","questionText":"6. How did the Philistines combine their knowledge and fear of God with superstition? Give examples of how believers and unbelievers do this today.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_8_7","questionText":"7. What happened once the ark was returned to Beth Shemesh (Israel)? How do believers trample on God's holiness today? (See Numbers 4:5-6, 20.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Numbers","verse":"4:5-6"},{"book":"Numbers","verse":"4:20"}]},{"id":"2018_8_8","questionText":"8. What do you learn about God's character in this passage? How does that encourage you in your present circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 7.\nSamuel led and interceded for Israel.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"7:1-17"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_8_9","questionText":"9. How did Samuel demonstrate godly leadership? Which examples will you implement with your family, children or others you lead?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_8_10","questionText":"10. How did the Israelites demonstrate faith and true repentance? What were the results?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_8_11","questionText":"11. Compare and contrast the battles in chapters 4 and 7. What lessons can you learn from these two battles?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 8.\nSamuel warned the Israelites of the consequences for insisting on an earthly king.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"8:1-22"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_8_12","questionText":"12. Why did the Israelites ask for a king? What did Samuel say would be the cost of having a king?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_8_13","questionText":"13. What do you learn about God or people in this passage?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_8_14","questionText":"14. How do believers try to be like the world today? At what cost?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 1 Samuel 4-8.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"4:1-8:22"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_8_15","questionText":"15. How did this week's study impact your thinking about repentance, grace, faith or obedience?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}